American Book Company Records
American Book Company Records
- Books
  - Books published by the American Book Company, original accession, 1801-1971 (Box 252-551, 821)
    Click here to open the spreadsheet for the initial accession. Also includes Oversize 1-B.
  - Books published by the American Book Company, 1998 accession, 1801-1971 (Box 558-818)
    Click here to open the spreadsheet for the 1998 accession; this list does not include names of any authors.
- Illustrations
  - Photographs, both original and reproduction, with a wide range of formats, dates and subject matter from pigs to streetcars; likely used in books published by ABC (Box 552)
  - Illustrations commissioned by the American Book Company for use in its publications, 1801-1964 (Oversize 8-1200)
    These boxes contain illustrations commissioned by the American Book Company for use in its publications (see the main Scope and Content description above for a list of authors and book titles whose illustrations are included here). The material is arranged in order by plate number but oversize plates have been relocated to the end and the series also includes unnumbered plates and plates identified only by book title. To simplify locating all relevant information, this section of the inventory is presented in the form of two spreadsheets, which can be sorted either by box number and plate number (click here) or by subject matter and plate number (click here). The spreadsheets do not reference the plates by artist and does not correlate plate numbers and publications.
    See also Miscellanea: Artwork above for a few other examples of images used in ABC books.
- Study charts
  - Study charts, 51 rolls, 1 tripod
- Miscellanea
  - Artwork, photograph and print, apparently used in World History Since 1870 (Box 819)
  - Artwork, camera-ready map mounted on cardboard entitled "A Map of New England" prepared by the Hagstrom Company of New York, which appeared in The Puritans by Perry Miller and Thomas Johnson published in 1938 (Map-case 131)
  - Book covers, samples of covers for hardcover and paperback textbooks on a variety of topics, including college texts, foreign languages, math and science, grammar, spelling, etc.; 7 folders (Box 819)
  - Bylaws, 1965 (Box 819)
  - Clippings, 1966; 1981; acquisition of ABC by Litton; Litton's sale of ABC to Thomson; Thomson's sale of ABC assets to D.C. Heath (Raytheon) (Box 819)
  - Letterhead, corporate (Box 819)
  - Notebook: "Movements of Private Car, Anthracite", 1914-1917 (Oversize 1-B)
  - "Our Heritage", 4 Jan 1947; address delivered to the company by W.W. Livegood, editor-in-chief and vice president (Box 819)
  - "Our Language Today" packet, covers, content, teacher's guide, etc. (Box 820)
  - Perception cards (Oversize 7)
    Story Hour Readers Perception Cards. Primer, First Year-First Half; Story Hour Readers Perception Cards. Book One, First Year-Second Half
  - Pins, commemorative pins given to10-year employees (Box 820)
  - Posters (Oversize 6)
    Wall posters to accompany Stoddard, Bailey, Lewis, McPherson English Series; Krusi’s Industrial Drawing Elementary Architecture Complete; Alphabetical Register no.1; American School Daily Weekly and Quarterly Register
  - Printing plates, ABC logo, decorations, etc.; 5 items in 2 folders (Box 820)
  - School catalog, 1970-1971 (Box 820)
  - "You and Your Company", 1956; corporate overview for new employees (Box 820)
  - Miscellaneous artifacts, 1956; loupe, ruler/square, etc. (Box 820)